<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Our Research on UK Health Security Agency</title><link>https://research.ukhsa.gov.uk/our-research/</link><description>Recent content in Our Research on UK Health Security Agency</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 09:24:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://research.ukhsa.gov.uk/our-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Burden of Disease caused by Damp and Mould in English Housing</title><link>https://research.ukhsa.gov.uk/our-research/damp-and-mould/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 09:24:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://research.ukhsa.gov.uk/our-research/damp-and-mould/</guid><description>The burden of disease caused by damp and mould in English housing In England, there are around 2 million people currently living in homes with significant damp and/or mould (3-4% of residences). While living in a damp and/or mouldy home is associated with the development or exacerbation of several respiratory diseases, conditions and symptoms, little is known about the burden of disease at a national scale in England.
Research led by scientists from the Air Quality and Public Health team, Environmental Hazards and Emergency Department and the Toxicology Department assessed the burden of asthma, lower respiratory infections, and allergic rhinitis from exposure to damp and/or mould in England in 2019 and by looking back several years in time.</description></item><item><title>Microphysiological Systems for Infectious Disease Modelling</title><link>https://research.ukhsa.gov.uk/our-research/microphysiological-systems/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 09:09:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://research.ukhsa.gov.uk/our-research/microphysiological-systems/</guid><description>Microphysiological Systems UKHSA Scientists at the UKHSA Vaccine Development Evaluation Centre are using advanced cell culture techniques to grow human organ systems in the laboratory. These organ systems will allow vaccine, drug, and therapeutic developers to evaluate how well their products can protect humans from infectious disease before embarking on clinical trials, whilst also addressing the ethical requirement to replace or reduce the use of animals wherever possible.
This is a step change from more traditional techniques and supports meeting UKHSA's requirements as signatory to the Concordat on Openness on Animal Research in the UK Microphysiological systems development that has been running alongside traditional screening techniques at UKHSA for several years.</description></item><item><title>COVID-19</title><link>https://research.ukhsa.gov.uk/our-research/covid-19/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 12:15:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://research.ukhsa.gov.uk/our-research/covid-19/</guid><description>COVID-19 UKHSA has conducted over 150 research and surveillance studies, most in collaboration with academics, to better understand SARS CoV-2 virus and its transmission.
We have published or submitted over 200 new research papers, commentaries and editorials on all aspects of the SARS CoV-2 virus, the illness it causes and how to mitigate the impacts of the pandemic.
Below is one of many studies contributing to the scientific knowledge base for the virus.</description></item></channel></rss>